<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Timeline on Marius Chiriac</title><link>https://mariuschiriac.github.io/posts/unity/timeline/</link><description>Recent content in Timeline on Marius Chiriac</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 06:21:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mariuschiriac.github.io/posts/unity/timeline/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Concatenate Timeline</title><link>https://mariuschiriac.github.io/posts/unity/timeline/concatenate/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 06:21:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mariuschiriac.github.io/posts/unity/timeline/concatenate/</guid><description>Someway you will need split one timeline into multiple in order to execute different timeline variants with less assets on the bag.
Coroutine that plays 2 timeline at correct time playableDirector.playableAsset = info.timeline[0]; PrepareTimeline(); playableDirector.Play(); yield return new WaitForSeconds((float)playableDirector.playableAsset.duration * Time.timeScale); playableDirector.playableAsset = info.timeline[1]; PrepareTimeline(); playableDirector.Play(); playableDirector is the reference to the PlayableDirector unity component. PrepareTimeline() is a method that fill the timeline&amp;rsquo;s clips with the instanced gameobjects. playableDirector.</description></item><item><title>Unity Timeline</title><link>https://mariuschiriac.github.io/posts/unity/timeline/base/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 06:15:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mariuschiriac.github.io/posts/unity/timeline/base/</guid><description>Timeline is a powerfull unity tool that permit to create a temporal sequence of instructions.
Create Timeline Asset In Project right click and select Create&amp;gt;Timeline
That operation create a *.playable file that represent a timeline asset.
Timeline Tracks Here is the official doc about tracks
On the left side of a Timeline we can see which tracks are used. A Track is a type of clips and is shown in horizontal.</description></item><item><title>Change timeline dinamically</title><link>https://mariuschiriac.github.io/posts/unity/timeline/dinamic-timeline/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 06:15:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mariuschiriac.github.io/posts/unity/timeline/dinamic-timeline/</guid><description>To achieve this result, we need a controller that hold the PlayableDirector and fill the current/correct value to the interested Timeline before to play it. We will use custom PlayableAsset and PlayableBehaviour to add new behaviour into the Timeline
Create Custom Timeline Track Create the TrackAsset to create your custom line track in the timeline, so you will be able to right-click the left side timeline&amp;rsquo;s panel to see the action &amp;ldquo;MovementTrack&amp;rdquo; or what else you named your TrackAsset.</description></item></channel></rss>